David and Howard Arthur Lincoln Papers MS035
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
David and Howard Arthur Lincoln Papers
1930 -- 1952
1929 -- 1980
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Lincoln, Howard Arthur
MS035
1.45 Linear Feet 2 boxes
Arrangement
This collection is organized into two series: Howard Arthur Lincoln Personal Papers; and David Lincoln Personal Papers.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains photographs, documents, and memorabilia pertaining to Howard A. Lincoln (A1930) and David Lincoln (A1952), including baseballs, baseball caps, a beanie, honorary society induction certificates, invitations, NROTC publications, NROTC uniform accessories, photographs, a reunion book, and a scrapbook.
Related Materials
MS0029, NROTC/V-12 memorabilia, DCA
Biographical / Historical
Howard Arthur Lincoln (A1930) was a member of the Theta Delta Chi fraternity and Vice-President of his senior class. He was a member of the Ivy Society (Junior Honorary Society) and the Tower Cross (Junior Honorary Society). After graduating from Tufts, he taught English at Dean Academy (1930-1948), Billerica Junior High (1948-1957), and Denis-Yarmouth Regional High School (1957-1963). He was married to Florence Van Ummersen, and they had one son, David.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
NROTC; Ivy Society; Sword and Shield; Tower Cross; Theta Delta Chi; Alumni and alumnae; Alumni collections; University history; Lincoln, David; Lincoln, Howard Arthur
- Howard Arthur Lincoln Personal Papers, 1929 -- 1980; 1929 -- 1930; MS035.001; 1.45 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains Howard A. Lincoln's material is from the Class of 1930 and includes photographs, honorary society induction certificates, a reunion book, and a beanie. This series contains material pertaining to the Theta Delta Chi fraternity, the Ivy Society, the Tower Cross, the Class of 1930 Commencement and 50th reunion. It also contains documents describing the history of the Tufts plates sold to fund construction of Alumnae Hall.
  Arrangement
  This series is not arranged.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Certificate of Admittance to Ivy Society for Howard Lincoln, 1929; MS035.001.001.00001 (Box MS035 Shared 1)
  - Photographs of the Theta Delta Chi Fraternity, 1930; MS035.001.001.00002 (Box MS035 Shared 1)
  - Certificate of Initiation to Tower Cross for Howard Lincoln, 1930; MS035.001.001.00003 (Box MS035 Shared 1)
  - Advertisement for the Tufts College Plates and a history of the Tufts College Plates, 1931 -- 1942; MS035.001.001.00004 (Box MS035 Shared 1)
    Item related to Elizabeth van Ummersen (J1924)
  - Class of 1930 50th reunion bulletin, reunion photographs, and senior banquest brochure (Class of 1930), 1930 -- 1980; MS035.001.001.00005 (Box MS035 Shared 1)
  - Class of 1930 freshman beanie, MS035.001.002.00022 (Box MS035 Shared 2)
    This item belongs to Series 1 but is boxed with memorabilia from Series 2.
- David Lincoln Personal Papers, 1941 -- 1952; MS035.002; 1.45 Linear Feet
  This series contains David Lincoln's material pertaining to his time in the NROTC program at Tufts and his tours with the Navy. This includes a belt, an ID card, pins, naval publications, a ribbon, a scarf, and a scrapbook. Items related to NROTC have been cross referenced with the V-12/NROTC collection (MS029). David Lincoln's other material includes baseball caps, baseballs, and material related to the Sword and Shield Society and to the Class of 1952 Commencement.
  - Photograph of David Lincoln, 1950; MS035.002.001.00006 (Box MS035 Shared 1)
  - Watch Officer's Guide, 1941; MS035.002.001.00007 (Box MS035 Shared 1)
    Written by Capt. Russell Wilson, United States Navy. Published by United States Naval Institute: Annapolis, Maryland, 1941. Reference recommended for personal library of all Naval line officers, NROTC curriculum.
  - Certificate of Initiation to Sword and Shield Society for David Lincoln, 1949; MS035.002.001.00008 (Box MS035 Shared 1)
  - Marnavrex, 1950; MS035.002.001.00009 (Box MS035 Shared 1)
    Small publication for Summer Midshipman's training.
  - Midshipmen's practice cruise, information of cruise ports and The Festival of Britain, 1951; MS035.002.001.00010 (Box MS035 Shared 1)
    Small publications removed from inside cover of David Lincoln's scrapbook.
  - Commencement invitation, 1952; MS035.002.001.00011 (Box MS035 Shared 1)
  - Leather bound commencement program, 1952; MS035.002.001.00012 (Box MS035 Shared 1)
  - Armed Forces ID card, 1952; MS035.002.001.00013 (Box MS035 Shared 1)
  - Baseball, Tufts V. Quonset Flyers, 1905 -- 1950; MS035.002.002.00001 (Box MS035 Shared 2)
    Section 1 in box.
  - Baseball, Tufts V. Suffolk University, 1950-05-15; MS035.002.002.00002 (Box MS035 Shared 2)
    Section 2 in box.
  - Baseball, Tufts V. MIT, April, 1951; MS035.002.002.00003 (Box MS035 Shared 2)
    Section 3 in box.
  - Baseball, Tufts V. Amherst, 1951-04-25; MS035.002.002.00004 (Box MS035 Shared 2)
    Section 4 in box.
  - Baseball, Tufts V. MIT, 1951-05-05; MS035.002.002.00005 (Box MS035 Shared 2)
    Section 5 in box.
  - Baseball, Tufts V. W.P.I., 1951-05-17; MS035.002.002.00006 (Box MS035 Shared 2)
    Section 6 in box.
  - Baseball, Tufts V. U. Mass., 1952-05-17; MS035.002.002.00007 (Box MS035 Shared 2)
    Section 7 in box.
  - Baseball, Tufts V. Bowdoin, MS035.002.002.00008 (Box MS035 Shared 2)
    No date. Section 8 in box.
  - Hat band side post, 1952; MS035.002.002.00009 (Box MS035 Shared 2)
    One hat post with eagle and starts. Missing back. Section 9.
    Pins
  - Leiutenant J 9 collar bars, 1952; MS035.002.002.00010 (Box MS035 Shared 2)
    Two small collar bars, silver in color. Section 10 in box.
  - Leiutenant J 9 collar bars, 1952; MS035.002.002.00011 (Box MS035 Shared 2)
    Two collar bars, silver in color. Section 11 in box.
  - Overseas cap officer crest pin, 1952; MS035.002.002.00012 (Box MS035 Shared 2)
    Gold and silver pin with eagle, anchors and swords. Section 12 in box.
  - Midshipman blues lapel insignia pin, 1952; MS035.002.002.00013 (Box MS035 Shared 2)
    Gold anchor. Section 13 in box.
  - Ensign's collar bars, 1952; MS035.002.002.00014 (Box MS035 Shared 2)
    Two small bars, gold color. Section 14 in box.
  - Midshipman insignia pin, 1952; MS035.002.002.00015 (Box MS035 Shared 2)
    USN ROTC pin. Section 15 in box.
  - Scrapbook, 1949 -- 1952; MS035.002.002.00016 (Box MS035 Shared 2)
    This scrapbook contains photos and documents related to David Lincoln's travels as part of the NROTC.
  - Naval scarf, 1952; MS035.002.002.00017 (Box MS035 Shared 2)
    White silk scarf, part of Tufts NROTC uniform. extra information in location field: 39090011485121.
  - NROTC khaki belt, 1952; MS035.002.002.00018 (Box MS035 Shared 2)
    Khaki belt with metal clasp. "D.Lincoln" stenciled on insides of belt in black.
  - NROTC naval ribbon, 1952; MS035.002.002.00019 (Box MS035 Shared 2)
    NROTC visor accessory with gold anchor.
  - Blue Tufts baseball cap, 1952; MS035.002.002.00020 (Box MS035 Shared 2)
  - Navy blue Tufts baseball cap, 1952; MS035.002.002.00021 (Box MS035 Shared 2)